Hallelujah!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your time has been blessed!
That is Jesus for you.
Jesus desires to heal our wounds.
He desires to heal our wounds.
When I say 'wounds', I mean everything about you.
You need healing, deliverance, ‎blessing - just name it.
He desires to heal your wounds, that is, to free you.‎
But often we do not permit Him -
often we do not allow Him. ‎
It is not something where He can just come by Himself without your faith,
"Be healed, be delivered!"
No, it is not ‎possible.
He can’t just come and say, "Hey, are you sick? Be healed!"
No! He needs your attention.
The road ‎to that is not the easiest road.
There is anointing just everywhere -
more than enough.
Now, it is time for you to use your faith to put a demand on the anointing.
Your faith now!
The supply is more than the demand.
When just one person is demanding for something, "Oh, it is too much for me".
That is just it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let us quickly take a look at the book of Luke 17.‎
"Jesus said to His disciples: 'Things that cause people to stumble are bound to come...'"
It is a text you must read every second.
When you get home, just read it. When you read it, it will guide you.
All these little irritations that overwhelm you, what people say about you, what people do to you.
When you know this verse, it will continue to help you.
Jesus said to you.
You put your name where the message is personal.
Jesus said to me.
Read along with me. One, two, three.
Jesus said to me: Things that will cause me to ‎stumble are bound to come.‎
Can we read it together again.
Anytime you read the Bible, insert your name where the message is personal.
In this case, it is personal.
"Jesus said to His disciples" - you remove 'disciples' and insert your own name.
Jesus said to me: Things that will cause me to ‎stumble are bound to come.‎
If Jesus said this to you, what else again? What are you talking about?
What are you talking about?
This means, it is impossible to live this life without offence.
I like that.
Can you write it down! Because I know you’re a professor, you’re very educated.
This word is not something ‎you can put in your memory: It must go in your heart.‎
Write it on your paper.
I know you are a professor, you are very educated,
and the one who is talking to ‎you was your student ‎‏in the past:
"Ha! T.B. Joshua was my student. I taught him when he was in primary school."
Ok, sit down there.‎‏
Take your paper and write something down as it will help you.
It will help you.
We read it again before we proceed.
Are you there?
That is Luke 17:1.
Jesus said to me: Things that will cause me to ‎stumble are bound to come.‎
What does that mean to you?
It means that it is impossible for me, T.B. Joshua, to live this life without offence.‎
Tell your neighbour.
It is impossible for you to live among people without offence.
Offence can come in any way, whether you are wrong or right. ‎
I saw you when you were dancing - you had forgotten about offence.
That is why you were dancing like this.
I said, "Ah, see my sister, see my brother!"
Some people were dancing like this.
After you finished dancing - "Hm, I will deal with that sister!"
I know you.
I was laughing.
Some people were dancing like this.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I said, "Hey! Jesus, thank You!"
But after you finished dancing, you sat down like this.
"I will deal with him!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
But now that we are talking, you have forgotten about that.
I want you to forget all trouble forever.
This is the wall between you and your ‎salvation,
the wall between you and God.
A good Christian, a real Christian, should refuse to be offended in order not to offend ‎God. ‎
Tell your neighbour.
A real Christian, a good Christian, a true Christian, should refuse to be offended
in order not to offend ‎God.
MESSAGE TITLE: REFUSE TO BE OFFENDED
Where will you put offence? Is that not where God lives?
There is no other place - in the heart.‎
Where will you put offence? Where the Holy Spirit lives.
There is no other place where you can ‎put offence.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When we feel offended, we use our tongues out of bitterness, hatred and anger
to crush a close friendship,
to split our churches,
to shatter our marriages,
to crumble families and tear them apart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The people most offended are the people that were cheated.
It is when you are cheated, you get ‎offended.
The right people, good people, Christians are the ones.
The good people are being cheated and embarassed.
When we feel offended, we do not know that we are trapped.
That is when you begin to say, "I will deal with him. Ok, I have already dealt with him".
You do not know that you are trapped.
Offence is an instrument used by satan to ‎blind us on the reality.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you are offended, you see yourself concentrate and focus on the wrong done to ‎you,
forgetting the condition you are in.‎
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"Ah, why me? This is an insult! I can't believe it!"
"Why all this? Why now?"
Whereas he has cancer - he is no longer talking about the cancer in his body.
"Oh, why all this? Why? What can I do?"
"No! I trained him. I was the one who trained him from school and now he is a graduate."
"Now he has become rich. But when he first ‎came, he was living with me."
"I hosted him. I trained him. I sent him to London. Look at him, ‎he is a nice man."
Whereas he has diabetes - he is no longer talking about that.
He is talking about the wrong done to him. ‎
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Offence is very rampant due to lack of real love.
Due to what? [Real love!]
There is love and there is real love.
I mean, genuine love.
Real love forgets wrong so that there is hope for the future.‎
What is real love?
Real love forgets wrong.
Say to your neighbour.
Real love forgets wrong!
I can't hear you.
So that there is what?
So that there is hope for the future.
Real love ‎forgets wrong so that there is hope for the future. ‎
Jesus loves you.
To get out of your dry pit, you must let go of offence.‎
Tell your neighbour.
Tell your neighbor again.
To get out of your dry pit, you must let go of offence.‎
I can't hear you.
Do you know what I mean by getting out of your dry pit?
Your dry pit could be sickness,
your dry pit could be isolation,
your dry pit could be ‎poverty, hardship.
What is your dry pit? ‎
To get out of your dry pit, you must let go of offence.
Whether you are wrong or right, no ‎one is permitted to hold on to an offence. ‎
Now you have received but don’t forget that to maintain this blessing, you need God.
Like my Evangelist said:
"The best man in the world can only maintain unless God protects."
It is better not to achieve than to achieve and fall. ‎
Tell your neighbour.
It is better not to achieve than to achieve and fall.
This is your case.
You desire healing, you desire blessing.
He who desires victory must be ready for war.
You desire blessing, victory, protection, salvation, all of God’s ‎blessings.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Take it once again.
The best man in the world can only maintain unless God protects. ‎
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Rise up. Thank you.
Ask your neighbour: What will you do with this little counsel?‎
What will you do with this little counsel?‎
Ask your neighbour.
Will you ask your neighbour a simple question?
What will you do with this little counsel?‎
That is it.
To maintain, you need God.
It is better not to achieve than to achieve and fall.
What will you do with this counsel?
You have heard that a good Christian should refuse to be ‎offended.‎
A good Christian should refuse to be offended because you don’t want to offend God.
The ‎reason why you have to refuse to be offended is because you don’t want to offend God. ‎
You can't hold offence and talk to God.
You can't hold offence and hear from God.
‎It is not possible.‎
Because when you hold offence, your spirit is not free
and your spirit needs to be free to ‎contact the Spirit of God.
When you hold an offence, your spirit is in bondage.
Your ‎spirit needs to be free to be sensitive to the Spirit of God. ‎
Just like the little example I gave you:
When you hold an offence, seeing yourself focus and ‎concentrate on the wrong done to you,
forgetting the condition in which you are.
It is not possible to talk about two things.
You can't be talking about failure and at the ‎same time talking about success.
Once you are focusing and concentrating on the wrong done to you,
the condition in ‎which you are is silent.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
With all your heart, you have to receive.
When you talk with all your heart, the job is ‎half done.
When we start praying now and you begin to confess with all your heart, the job is half done.
You have scored fifty percent. ‎
Are you with me?
I want to repeat again.
When we say, "Okay, it is time to pray", and you begin to talk with all your ‎heart,
at that level, you have scored fifty percent, the job is half done. ‎
The SCOAN Sunday Service
But how will you talk with all your heart when your heart is not free -
when you find ‎yourself a hostage, in self-imprisonment because of an unforgiving spirit?
You are carrying ‎anger, hatred, bitterness against someone. ‎
You are here in the presence of God, carrying an unforgiving spirit,
carrying hatred, bitterness, jealousy against someone somewhere,
and you want to receive from God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God has already judged those who have offended you.
It is in that book when you read down: "Woe unto..."
Take your book and read.
He has judged already.
So, if God has laid judgment on those ‎who have offended you, why do you want to hassle?‎
It is there.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He said: "''...but woe to anyone through whom they come.'"
"Jesus said to His disciples: 'Things that cause ‎people to stumble are bound to come
but woe to anyone through whom they come.'"
What judgment again?
It is clear.‎
Below, the punishment has already been described there.
It is there when you read it ‎down. ‎
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you free?
Are you free now?
Before now, we were carrying anger, bitterness, hurt, deep ‎pain, deep hurt against someone.
Make sure that you are free now so that we can proceed.
Because we are about to enter ‎another level. ‎
You know when a pilot is flying, he will tell you he is going up - above the level he is now.
We are going up now.
Whatever you need to do now; please, get yourself free.
You ‎need to be free.
It makes the job easier.
To be free is fifty percent.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You can open your lips and say, "Lord Jesus, come into my heart, wash me with your ‎precious blood". Prayer!
Viewers all over the world!
We need to be free to contact the Spirit of God.
If your spirit ‎is not free, you cannot contact the Spirit of God.
Right now, say a simple prayer.
Lord Jesus, come into my heart, wash ‎me with your precious blood, save my soul today.
Prayer, viewers!
Viewers, I need to say the reason because I have not talked to you yet.
Listen - this is a message to you:
As a good Christian, ‎you should refuse to be offended in order not to offend Jesus.
It is true! Jesus said to you that it is not possible to live in this world without offence.
But in ‎order not to offend God, you should refuse to be offended.
So please open your lips right ‎now and say this word: "Lord Jesus!"
You know that I am not calling you a sinner.
Lord Jesus, come into my heart!
Wash me ‎with your precious blood!
Save my soul today!
Prayer!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Viewers, listen to me!
When we feel offended, we begin to use our tongues out of bitterness and ‎anger.
We begin to use our tongues to split relationships, shatter marriages ‎and tear families apart.
We split the ministry, churches with our tongues.
In the tongue, death ‎and life, as the Book of Proverbs 18:21 says.
‎Right now, say: Lord Jesus, come into my heart,
wash me with your precious blood,
save my soul today!
Prayer!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Into my heart
Come into my heart, Lord Jesus
Come in to stay
Come in today
Come into my heart, Lord Jesus
Into my heart
Come in to stay
Come in today
Come into my heart, Lord Jesus
Into my heart
Come in to stay
Come in today
Come into my heart, Lord Jesus
Into my heart
Come in to stay
Come in today
Come into my heart, Lord Jesus
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In Jesus Christ's name we pray.
Like I asked you - what is your dry pit?
When Joseph was in the dry pit, he said to himself, "This is not where I belong".
‎He was in the dry pit where there was no light, there was nothing.
He was there, saying to ‎himself what was in accordance with his dream and goal.
He had dreamt.
He knew what the vision was all ‎about for him.
He said to himself, "This is not where I belong. I know where I belong".
That statement comforted him.
You are supposed to be comforted ‎if you have a vision.
When we ‎‏say 'a poor man', it does not mean a man without money in the pocket but a man ‎without vision.
‎‏Whatever situation you are in, remember your dream and your goal.
Tell your neighbour.
Whatever situation you are in, remember your dream and your goal!
I can't hear you.
Whatever ‎‏situation you are in, remember your dream and your goal! ‎‏
When Joseph was in the dry pit, he said to himself, after remembering his dream and goal,
"This is ‎not ‎‏where I belong. I know where I belong!"
He laughed and said, "Ok, ok, ok! This is one of ‎‏the ten I will pass through to get to where I'm going".
Have you ever said to yourself before, standing in the face of storm and crisis,
"Hey, this is not where I belong. My dream does not suggest these.
This is not ‎where I belong! I ‎‏know where I belong!
Ok, just a stop-over. It is one of the states I must pass through.
It will not impair me but improve me!"
Your struggle will make you stronger.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Whoever asked yourself this?
But you never remember.
I mean, if you have a vision in your ‎dream, you ‎‏will remember.
Instead of lamenting, mourning, complaining, "Oh my God, ‎why this trouble?"
No! Remember your ‎goal and your dream whatever ‎‏the situation.
Joseph was in the dry pit and immediately that ‎situation reminded him of his dream and goal.
He said to himself, "Ah, I dreamt seeing a crown. I dreamt ‎wearing a crown.
I dreamt seeing myself on a throne.‏
This is not a throne. This is not where I ‎belong; I know where I belong!"
I know where I belong means, "Yes, I'm still going there!"
I know where I belong means, "Here ‎will ‎‏make me stronger!"
I know where I belong means, "This place will not impair me but improve me!"
Do you ever talk to yourself like that?
Each time you have no money, you begin to complain.
Each time there are challenges, you ‎begin to ‎‏complain.
‎‏You allow your situation to rule you.
You allow your situation to ‎dictate your direction.
Don't allow your situtation to rule you.
Tell your neighbour: "I know where I belong."
I know where I belong.
I can't hear you.
If you know where you belong, why are you complaining, murmuring?
Why are you lamenting over the ‎situation ‎you are in?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Why? Ask yourself.
If you know where you belong, that alone can give you joy and strength -
so much ‎strength to overlook the situation.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I say to you: He who desires victory must be ready for war.
So it is part of your war you ‎must ‎fight.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you with me?
Cancer can be part of the war.
Fever, setback, hardship, poverty, ‎‎disappointment
can be one of the ones you must fight to get to the throne.
Tell your neighbour: He who desires victory must be ready for ‎‎war.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When we say war, you may fight twenty wars to get to the throne, and you must ‎overcome each war.
If not, it ‎will give you setback.
You may fight twenty wars.
The ‎number of wars you fight may not be the number of wars I will fight.
You may fight twenty; I may fight hundred.
The nature of war you fight may not be the nature of war I ‎fight.
Yours can be ‎disappointment, hardship, people lying against you, going into prison and coming back.
It could be isolation, sickness, disease or affliction.
It could be that war you need to fight to get to the throne.
He who desires victory, he who desires a crown, he who desires to be in a palace
must be ‎ready to fight war.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Ask your neighbour: What is your present war now?
He should answer you; you should answer her.
What is your present war?
Answer your neighbour.
Yours could be ‎disappointment, setback, hardship, hatred.
What is your present war?
Nothing comes for nothing and nothing happens by chance.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Joseph found himself ‎in the dry pit as a ‎part of the war he had to fight.
He fought it, overcame and moved forward.
From that dry pit - the pit was not the last war.
He still went ahead to fight.
The dry pit was not the last war Joseph fought to get to the throne.
Are you saying the dry pit was the last war?
No!
Why are you troubled and crying?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The dry pit was not the last war.
That was why he said, "I know where I belong! This is ‎not where I belong. I know where I ‎belong".
He knew he had more battles to fight.
But in each ‎war, each battle, he remembered his goal, his vision.
Tell your neighbour: "Remember your vision!"
Remember your vision.
I can't hear you.
Nothing is much more than your vision.
Nothing is much more ‎than your goal.
I can't hear you.
Nothing is much more ‎than your vision and your ‎goal.
Yes.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is better not to achieve than to achieve and fall.
Thank you. You may be seated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How can anybody that listened to that message still be complaining over the situation
when you know where ‎you belong!
You will soon leave that situation, the situation will soon leave ‎you.
Amen.
That is it!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You will leave the situation ‎and the situation will leave you.
You know ‎where you belong!
That is not where you belong.
Soldier on!
You will meet another situation after this.
You ‎will meet another ‎situation probably greater than the one you are facing now.
It determines the type of crown you are prepared for.
A greater crown ‎attracts greater persecution.
So, that is it.
You are talking as if this is the last war you will fight to get to the palace.
This is the way you talk now - as if you are fed up.
"This is the last battle" - I don't know whether this is the last battle you will fight to get to the palace,
to get to your destination.
Many of us don’t know what it means to say, "Joseph was in the dry pit".
That pit was ‎not the last battle. ‎
He left the dry pit and then soldiered on to another battle, ‎another greater situation.
We that maintain the relationship with God are enabled.
Anybody that maintains the relationship - if today you say, "I want to be a friend of God.
I want to be with God" - you will be enabled to endure.
There is a grace.
It maintains the ‎relationship.
If you confess genuinely and follow Him - not just like people ‎that confess, "Jesus is my Lord" -
there is a package for you.
No one follows Jesus without enablement.
The test and hardship that confront your daily life - there is enablement.
Enablement means strength, ability.
He doesn't leave us ‎just like that.
He has giving each and ‎everyone enablement.
Why should we complain?
When you follow Him, He gives you enablement.
You can't just follow Him without enablement.
That enablement is to give you endurance and ‎overcoming.
So ‎when you see people complaining, it means they are not genuinely born again.
If you are ‎genuinely ‎born again, there is enablement given to you -
that is ability, strength, given to ‎you to be His children
and that ‎enablement will give you endurance.
That enablement ‎will give you power to overcome.
It was that ‎enablement that gave Joseph endurance, ‎to endure the situation in the dry pit.
If not, he would have died there, not enduring the situation in the dry pit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You are living and talking as if the life you live is yours.
Once you are born again, the ‎life you are living is ‎not yours but Christ's.
It means that when you are born again, you follow ‎Christ.
It means that someone is somewhere seeing ‎you through.
Someone is somewhere fighting for you.
Someone is somewhere protecting you.
You may not see it but He is somewhere seeing you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Can you be bold enough to say, "I know where I belong!"
I know where I belong.
Do you know the meaning?
It means that the situation you are in now, is not yours.
You will soon get out of that and move forward.
Say to yourself, "I know where I belong".
I know where I belong.
Where you belong - that is ‎the question.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So ‎please, you need to talk to yourself.
Talking to yourself is better ‎than even a pastor talking to you.
You are not used to talking to yourself.
I am talking to you but if you ‎talk to yourself with all your heart,
it is more powerful ‎than a pastor talking to you.
You need ‎to talk to yourself.
When you get home today, you need to ‎meditate over and over the message you received today.
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances,
sermons and testimonies from The SCOAN.
Emmanuel TV - Changing lives, Changing nations and Changing the world.